Contact

401-741-5635 (Mobile) cnorrn246@icloud.com

www.linkedin.com/in/carolynnobrega-bsn-cnor-rn-405853102 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Management
Educator Operating Room
Perioperative Nursing

Languages

English

Certifications CNOR

Publications

Created/Implemented Orientation Booklet for newly hired Travel/ Permanent RN/Surgical Technicians

Created/Implemented Fire Risk Assessment/Policy/Competency at MHRI

Carolyn Nobrega BSN,CNOR,RN

Nurse Manager Surgical, Endoscopic, Central Sterile Services and OR Materials Management at Sturdy Memorial Hospital Attleboro, Massachusetts

Summary

Accomplished Registered Nurse with 28 years experience licensed in Rhode Island and Massachusetts. Introduction to Surgical Services in 2002 created a passion and enthusiasm for positions in Operating Room with advancement toward leadership roles.

Currently holding the position of Manager Surgical, Endoscopic And Central Sterile Reprocessing Services at Sturdy Memorial Hospital, Attleboro, MA. since November, 2018. Other positions held in OR include; Patient Care Manager of Surgical Services Charlton Memorial Hospital 3/2016 - 11/2018. Nurse Specialist/ Operating Room Nurse Educator with primary responsibility of implementing and teaching AORN PeriOp 101 program as well as assisting surgical services with Joint Commission Preparedness at Carney Hospital, Dorchester, MA, Assistant Clinical Nurse Manager of Operating Room/Operating Room Educator as well as Clinical Coordinator and Board Runner of Operating Room from 10/2012 - 7/2015, circulator, scrub nurse, team leader, OB/GYN coordinator, ambulatory/pain procedures and recovery at MHRI, Pawtucket, RI. Responsible for creating and implementing Fire Risk Policy and competency at MHRI.

Developed strong leadership and clinical skills including assessment, intervention and evaluation on Medical/Surgical unit specializing in Orthopedics and Respiratory. Experience also includes Outpatient Care in IV and Chemotherapy Administration at MHRI. Worked per diem for The Miriam Hospital IV team. Excellent communication skills both verbal and written. Highly approachable, diplomatic and motivated. Continued interest in managerial and/or leadership role within perioperative services, higher education and/or health care industry. Eager to matriculate as necessary.

Page 1 of 4

Experience

Sturdy Memorial Hospital

Nurse Manager Surgical, Endoscopic, Central Sterile Services and OR Materials Management

November 2018 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Attleboro, Massachusetts

Southcoast Health

Patient Care Manager Surgical Services

March 2016 - November 2018 (2 years 9 months)

Steward Health Care

Clinical Nurse Specialist/Operating Room Nurse Educator - Contract/Interim

September 2015 - March 2016 (7 months)

Greater Boston Area

Contracted to implement and teach AORN PeriOp 101 course in Operating Room Carney Hospital, circulating, scrubbing cases as needed, assisting with Joint Commission Preparedness. Responsible for obtaining National Patient Safety Goals data, Chart Audits, Real time "Time Out" Audits in the operating room.

Float to other departments under Surgical Services to assist as necessary such as Interventional Radiology as well as Minor Procedures Unit.

Participated as clinical leader with Presentation/Competency on Malignant Hyperthermia in the Operating Room for Specialized Nursing Departments within the hospital.

Schedule in-services with purpose of educating Operating Room Staff regarding new equipment, instrumentation or technology as well as remedial change and development.

Care New England

13 years 5 months

Assistant Clinical Nurse Manager/Operating Room Educator June 2012 - July 2015 (3 years 2 months)

Pawtucket, RI

Worked as Interim ACNM/OR Educator June 2012 accepting position permanently October 2012. Supervise/Educate OR staff. Implemented/
Teaching AORN Peri Op 101 Course, training inexperienced RNs and surgical techs. Participate in recruitment and hiring of permanent and travel staff.
Manage/review/evaluate employees, Podiatric surgical residents and New

England Surgical Tech students in sterile field as well as processes within the operating room. Assist in revising/creating policies and procedures. Created and implemented Fire Policy, Fire Risk Assessment and Fire Competency at MHRI. Acts as clinical coordinator of OR, with keen ability to facilitate cases and run inner core smoothly. Excellent rapport with surgeons/physicians and colleagues. Strong leadership and communication skills both verbal and written.

PeriOp Registered Nurse

March 2002 - October 2012 (10 years 8 months)

Pawtucket, RI

Circulate/Scrub surgical cases to assist surgeons and anesthesia teams in all specialties including; General, Gynecological, Neurological, Podiatric, ENT, Cystology, Urology, Vascular, Thoracic, Orthopedic and Ophthalmic surgery. Responsible for 24 hour on call / weekly basis. Gynecological Specialty Coordinator. Scrub all GYN cases including C-Sections. Scrub some Podiatry and General cases based on staffing needs. Coordinator/Facilitator and Team Leader of Inner Core Operating Room.

PeriOp RN/Pain Management RN/Recovery RN June 2008 - October 2008 (5 months)

Notre Dame Campus, Central Falls RI

Outpatient Ambulatory Care/Pain Clinic/Recovery RN
Circulating/Scrubbing Podiatry and Ophthalmic surgery. Assisting
Anesthesiologist, recovery of patients undergoing pain management
procedures requiring monitored anesthesia care. ACLS certification required
for this position.

Notre Dame Clinic moved to main campus in October of 2008.

Lifespan

IV Team/ IV RN Per Diem
March 2001 - March 2002 (1 year 1 month)

The Miriam Hospital, Providence RI

IV Therapy Nurse

Available throughout Magnet Hospital to obtain/maintain IV access for patients on daily basis as well as emergently in all specialty areas as needed.

Care New England

11 years 8 months

Hematology/Oncology Registered Nurse January 1999 - January 2002 (3 years 1 month)

Outpatient Infusion Treatment

Hematology/Oncology Registered Nurse Outpatient Infusion Treatment Unit. Responsible for accessing/de-accessing port-a-caths; performing therapeutic phlebotomy and peripheral bloodwork; accessing IV for administering infusions including; chemotherapy, PRBC, platelets, plasma IgG, antibiotics, Desferral, Gemcitabine and numerous IV medications. Also responsible for administering injections including Epogen, Neupogen and Vitamin B12. This position required Chemotherapy Certification, Excellent communication skills and advanced IV accessing skills.

Medical/Surgical Registered Nurse
June 1990 - February 1999 (8 years 9 months)
MHRI Campus

Staff Nurse on Medical/Surgical Unit specializing in orthopedic and respiratory cases. Initial and ongoing assessment of patients recovering from surgery as well as ventilated patients. Developed strong clinical skills including assessment, intervention and evaluation. Developed, implemented and evaluated plan of care delivered by LPNs and CNAs.

Education

Rhode Island College

Bachelor's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1992 - 1994)